Cesar Alvarez Diaz

(760) 625 - 3248 51 Wellesley Irvine, CA 92612

cesarlcdiaz@gmail.com

Highly qualified front end web development professional with 3 years of experience creating self-taught projects utilizing HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Frameworks, and developed web based projects. Currently seeking a position in the Orange County Area. Portfolio Available on Github: https://github.com/cesarlcdiaz

Front End Web Development:

- Photoshop
- HTML5
- CSS3
- Javascript
- Bootstrap

- MongoDB
- Express
- AngularJs
- NodeJs
- JQuery

- Dreamweaver
- Git/JIRA
- Wordpress
- Google API
- Google Analytics
- Spanish

Professional Experience

Bright.Coach--10/01/2016-1/16/2017

Web Developer/ 4 month Contract -- Laguna Beach

- Collaborated on improving the existing site into mobile responsiveness
- Integrated social media applications on websites and blogs
- Created a custom blog page in Wordpress framework
- Tested front-end code in multiple browsers to ensure cross-browser compatability.
- Maintained brand standards under company guidelines.
- Developed dynamic and interactive website that ensured high traffic, page views, and User Experience.

Johnglover.photography --10/24--10/26/2016

Web Developer/ Freelance Contract -- Santa Ana, CA.

- Completed desktop & mobile responsive Wordpress & Bootstrap website under 3 days timeline & under budget .
- Created CMS that enabled clients to update website as needed without code.
- Developed dynamic and interactive website that ensured high traffic, page views, and User Experience.
- Tested front-end code in multiple browsers to ensure cross-browser compatability.
- Maintained brand standards under company guidelines.
- Integrated social media applications on websites and blogs.

Socal UX Camp -- 8/6/2016

Volunteer -- Irvine, CA.

- Help Preparations for 500+ students.
- Work alongside professionals. Aiding and assisting students.
- Provide student information/directions.

Firstpage Web Listings -- 2/5/2016 - 6/30/2016

Web Developer / 5 month contract -- Santa Ana, CA.

- Developed dynamic and interactive website that ensured high traffic, page views, and User Experience, resulting in 40% increase in sales revenue.
- Utilizing frameworks such as wordpress and bootstrap.
- Updating features and optimizing 50+ existing and new websites.
- Working alongside clients to meet expectations.
- Front-end development using latest HTML5 and CSS3 techniques, backed by jQuery and other Javascript frameworks to enable optimum user experience throughout the site.
- Cross-browser support and unit testing to ensure quality work.

www.vinnynail.com -- 3/10/2011 - 4/23/2013

Web developer -- Palm Desert, CA.

- Created and manage a business website using Wordpress, HTML5, CSS3.
- Added & Edited coupons and sales.

Education

Treehouse -- 11/5/2015- Present

Full stack javascript Track Student -- Online

 Took courses on HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap, MongoDB, Angularjs, Express & Gulp and developed projects.

Udemy -- 11/15/2015

Courses Taken: NodeJs, & JavaScript--The Weird Parts.

O'Reilly School of Technology -- 2/5/2015 - 7/3/2015

Java Basics Student -- Online

- Created a Calculator Program, Drawing Pad program that recreated cartoon characters using Cartesian Coordinates, & "Hello World" program
- Learned Syntax & Object-Oriented Java through implementation of projects.

College of the Desert -- 10/2/2010- 4/19/2014

Student -- Palm Desert, CA.

• Computer Information Systems.